<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>IT on The Lennons Wiki</title>
    <link>https://lennon101.github.io/categories/it/</link>
    <description>Recent content in IT on The Lennons Wiki</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 13:09:00 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://lennon101.github.io/categories/it/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Proxmox Email Alerts Setup </title>
      <link>https://lennon101.github.io/posts/my-first-post---copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 13:09:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lennon101.github.io/posts/my-first-post---copy/</guid>
      <description>1. Install mailutils SSH into proxmox node and become root user. Run the following commands to download extra software dependencies we&amp;rsquo;ll need.&#xA;```bash apt update apt install -y libsasl2-modules mailutils ``` 2. Enable 2FA for the gmail account. This is the account that will be used by proxmox to send emails. Go to security settings&#xD;3. Create app password for the account. 1. Go to [App Passwords](https://security.google.com/settings/security/apppasswords) 2. Select app: `Mail` 3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Securing Your Nas Against Ransomware</title>
      <link>https://lennon101.github.io/posts/securing-your-nas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 10:39:36 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lennon101.github.io/posts/securing-your-nas/</guid>
      <description>Threat I&amp;rsquo;m on a synology sub-reddit&#xD;page and I see posts like this every couple of months and it terrifies me:&#xA;This is an example of Ransomware. Ransomware is a type of malicious software designed to block access to a computer system or files until a sum of money, or &amp;ldquo;ransom,&amp;rdquo; is paid. It typically works by encrypting the victim&amp;rsquo;s files or locking them behind a password, rendering them inaccessible. Once the ransomware is activated, the victim is presented with instructions on how to pay the ransom, often in cryptocurrency, in exchange for a decryption key or password.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Windows 10 Search Bar Not Loading</title>
      <link>https://lennon101.github.io/posts/windows-10-search-bar-not-loading-fix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 11:05:00 +1000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lennon101.github.io/posts/windows-10-search-bar-not-loading-fix/</guid>
      <description>What happened The Search menu on my Windows 10 suddenly stopped working. When I clicked the Search icon or type something in the Start menu, it just shows a blank search window. The fix Right click on the windows key and tap Run Open the Registery Editor by typing regedit and tapping ok Navigate to:&#xA;HKEY_CURRENT_USER\SOFTWARE\Microsoft\Windows\CurrentVersion\Search Right-click the Search icon and choose New &amp;gt; DWORD (32-bit) Value. Name the new value: BingSearchEnabled Double-click the new BingSearchEnabled value to open its properties dialog.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
